Gerardo Garcia

Self-Taught Programmer with an eye for design.

Los Angeles, CA 90022 gergarcia9@gmail.com +1 213 294 8744

I have had many roles in my web development career - developer, designer, media manager, and marketing manager. I have worked on almost every aspect of building and maintaining a company's presence on line - sales, marketing, customer relations, content creation, and most importantly website building and maintenance. I am the perfect bridge between the sales, design, marketing and developer teams!

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Freelance Web Developer

Los Angeles, CA May 2021 to 2024

- Self-taught programmer.
- I have built projects for small businesses using HTML, CSS, Javascript, REACT, SASS, and MYSQL.
- I have worked with clients in coming up with a design for their project as well as building it out for them.
- Experience with setting up Linux servers to host these sites (I am comfortable with the command line), allowing me to truly create a custom web experience for my clients without limitations.
- I am a self starter, self-learning and self-directed individual. If there is one thing I can call myself an expert in, it is in learning new concepts and skills.

Web Design and Marketing

Oranges & Lemons LLC - Los Angeles, CA April 2016 to March 2020

- Oranges and Lemons is a small business that focusing on residential and office cleaning services.
- I was in charge of building and maintaining the company website. s I used very basic HTML and CSS to modify a Weebly built webpage.
- I integrated various 3rd party applications: chatbot for customer service, call to actions, booking page connections and employee time management and tracking software.
- Managed the Customer Retention Management Systems, Google Ads, Google Business, Yelp and was in charge of making sure the booking experience was a seamless and stress free one.
- I also made sure that we had a functioning customer service system, one that was accessible both online and through our mobile application.

Education

College Degree in Geology

Pasadena City College

August 2016 to Present

High school diploma

August 2002 to June 2006

Skills

- Furniture Design
- Sketchup
- Carpentry
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Web design
- Graphic Design
- Photography
- Google Ads
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Google Analytics
- Adobe InDesign
- · Digital Marketing
- Adobe Dreamweaver
- HTML5 (3 years)
- Web development (4 years)
- Front-end development (4 years)
- JavaScript (1 year)
- CSS (3 years)
- WordPress
- XML
- Git
- Adobe Creative Suite (6 years)
- APIs
- GitHub (1 year)
- User Interface (UI)
- E-commerce
- Email marketing (4 years)
- MailChimp (4 years)
- Google Search Console (5 years)

- Usability
- Adobe XD
- SCSS (1 year)
- A/B testing
- MySQL (Less than 1 year)
- Laravel (Less than 1 year)
- Vue.js (Less than 1 year)
- Nuxtjs (Less than 1 year)
- TailwindCSS (Less than 1 year)

Languages

• Spanish - Fluent

Links

http://gerardogarcia.info

https://github.com/gerardojgarcia